Guide to the Ira Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ira Cohen papers
1924-2007
YCAL MSS 625
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
132.64
(203 boxes) + 14 broadside, 2 record album storage, and 1 art
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, notebooks, photographs, artwork, objects, audiovisual materials, and electronic media the document the life and work of Ira Cohen. The papers include materials relating to other writers, artists, and groups including Ronnie Burk, Louise Landes-Levi, the Living Theatre, Gerard Malanga, Petra Vogt, Tom Weigel, various Beat generation writers, and others. Artwork includes mail art, paintings, drawings, screen prints, and posters. Objects include stamps, Cohen's typewriter, masks, and plaster and papier mache casts. Casts include life masks made by Cohen of friends including Allen Ginsberg and Julian Beck and a cast of William S. Burroughs' hand.
Cohen, Ira.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Johan Kugelberg on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2011.
Information about Access
This material is open for research.
Boxes 44, 93-97, 185-213 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 98, 214-219 (digital media): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Ira Cohen
Ira Cohen (1935-2011) was an American poet, photographer, publisher, and filmmaker. He was associated with the Living Theatre, as well as various writers associated with the Beat generation.
Description of the Papers
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, notebooks, photographs, artwork, objects, audiovisual materials, and electronic media the document the life and work of Ira Cohen. The papers include materials relating to other writers, artists, and groups including Ronnie Burk, Louise Landes-Levi, the Living Theatre, Gerard Malanga, Petra Vogt, Tom Weigel, various Beat generation writers, and others. Artwork includes mail art, paintings, drawings, screen prints, and posters. Objects include stamps, Cohen's typewriter, masks, and plaster and papier mache casts. Casts include life masks made by Cohen of friends including Allen Ginsberg and Julian Beck and a cast of William S. Burroughs' hand.
Arrangement
Organized into eleven series: I. Selected Papers, 1924, 1960s-2000s. II. Correspondence, 1970s-2000s. III. Papers Relating to Other Writers and Groups, 1960s-2000s. IV. Manuscript Materials and Working Files, circa 1961-2007. V. Notebooks, 1979-2005. VI. Photographs, 1960s-2000s. VII. Papers Removed from Printed Material, undated. VIII. Artwork, 1970s-2000s. IX. Objects, circa 1936, 1980s-2000s. X. Audiovisual Materials, 1965-2000s. XI. Electronic Media, 1980s-2000s.
- Selected papers, 1924, 1960s-2000s; Series I; 6
  Scope and Contents
  These materials were selected by Johan Kugelberg for use in a master class taught at the Beinecke Library in 2011.
  - Gerald Malanga journal; Morocco; On Feet of Gold; Mail Art; Poetry; sunglasses, and passport, 1924, 1960s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Poetry, photographs, correspondence and postcards, mail art and writings, 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Photographs, Living Theater material, poetry ephemera, correspondence, printed material, and mail art, 1970s-2000s (Box 3)
  - Photograph, "John Brockmeyer as the Magician," "How to draw sheep," correspondence, Hashish Cook Book negatives, water color, and posters, 1980s (Box 4 (Oversize))
  - Map, "the direction of beauty + the beauty of direction", 2000s (Box 5 (Broadside))
  - Correspondence, Laurel and Hardy photographs, typescript, printed materials, "Conversation with Paul Bowles" proofs, 1970s-2000s (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1970s-2000s; Series II; 35
  - Correspondence, photographs, postcards, and mail art, 1970s-2000s (Box 7)
  - Map/calendar, artwork, photograph, and poster, 1970s-2000s (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - Poetry, mail art, correspondence, and photographs, 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed material, 1970s-2000s (Box 10)
  - Várnai György cartoons, photostats, pen and ink drawing, poetry scrolls, prints, and mail art, 1980s-2000s (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed material, 1980s-2000s (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed material, 1980s 2000s (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, photographs, postcards, printed material, and mail art, 1990s-2000s (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, photographs, postcards, printed material, and mail art, 1990s-2000s (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, photographs, and ink drawing by John Hersey, 1980s-2000s (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed material, 2000s (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed materials, 1980s-2000s (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, postcards, mail art, photographs, and printed material, 1980s-2000s (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, mail art, photographs, printed material, and print with letter by Gerard Bellaart, 1980s-2000s (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, mail art, photographs, and printed material, 1980s-2000s (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, postcards, mail art, photographs, printed material, and slides, 1990s-2000s (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, and news clippings, 1980s-2000s (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, news clippings, and photographs, 1980's-2000's (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, postcards, mail art, photographs, and printed material, 1970s-2000s (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, news clippings, and photographs, 1980s-2000s (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1980s-2000s (Box 27)
    Correspondents include Arnold Barkus and Gaby, Caliban - Lawrence Smith, Le Court d'Alcyon, Nina Zivancevic, Uri Hertz - Jack M., Carl Hanni, Dario Stipisic, Randy Roark, Rizzi, John Peňuelas, Bill Devore, Jane Falk, A Codrescu, John Brandi, New Guinea - carol B., Timothy Baum, NEXUS - Larry Sawyer, Stuart Newton, Roberto Valenza, Florian Vetsch, Phillippe Franck
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, news clippings, and photographs, 1980s-2000s (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, printed material, and photographs, 1980s-2000s (Box 29)
  - Writings, the Dolphin and the Bay, the Berber King, printed materials, photocopies, photographs, correspondence, mail art, postcards, and Paris travel guide, 1970s-2000s (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, typescripts, printed material, photographs, and mail art, 1980s-2000s (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, mail art, and printed material, 1990s (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, photographs, writings, postcards, mail art, printed material, and art, 1970s-2000s (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, photographs, writings, postcards, mail art, and printed material, 1970s-2000s (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, mail art, printed material, and photographs, 1980s-1990s (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, printed material, and photographs, 1980s-1990s (Box 36)
  - Correspondence, printed material, photographs, and mail art, 1970s-2000s (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, photographs, writings, postcards, mail art, and printed materials, 1970s-2000s (Box 38)
  - Correspondence, printed material, photographs, and mail art, 1980s-2000s (Box 39)
  - Correspondence, printed material, photographs, and mail art, 1980s-2000s (Box 40)
  - Correspondence, mail art, photographs, postcards, printed material, "If I Am The Whole-E Mother!," "Poems For the Glancing Eye," photocopies, clippings, and fishing flies, 1970s-2000s (Box 41)
- Papers relating to other writers and groups, 1960s-2000s; Series III; 18
  - Beat generation writers
    Writings, correspondence, artwork, and other papers relating to Beat writers including Jack Hirschman, Janine Pommy Vega, Terry Wilson, Michael McClure, Don Synder, Diane di Prima, R. Horowitz, Penny Arcade, Kush, Jackson Mac Low, Roberto Valenza, Roy L. Walford, Jerome Rothenberg, Gregory Corso, and others.
    - Correspondence, mail art, postcards, printed material, news clippings, writings, and drawings, 1970s-2000s (Box 42)
    - Drawings, poems, and posters (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Living Theatre
    - Footage of "Paradise Now" shot by Marty Topp and Ira Cohen, 1970s
    - Printed material, typescript, 1970s-1980s (Box 45)
    - Correspondence, printed material, ephemera, Julian Beck typescript poetry, and Ira Cohen's photographs of The Living Theater cast in the 1980s, 1970s-1990s (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, writings, interview, clippings, photographs, prints, postcards, and posters, 1970s-2000s (Box 47)
    - V Magazine (2007), Keppler print (1979), 1979; 2007 (Box 48 (Oversize))
  - Ken Brown, Harold Norse, Robert LaVigne, Lionel Ziprin
    - Typescripts, manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, slides, Livigne originals, prints, and watercolors, 1970s-1990s (Box 49)
    - Typescripts, manuscripts, correspondence, photographs, slides, Livigne originals, prints, and watercolors, 1970s-1990's (Box 50)
  - Ronnie Burk
    - Writings, mail art, correspondence, postcards, clippings, and photocopies, 1990s-2000s (Box 51)
    - Posters, 1990s (Box 48 (Oversize))
  - Tom Weigel
    - Typescripts, manuscripts, printed material, 1973-2006 (Box 52)
  - Gerard Malanga
    - Correspondence, printed material, and photographs, 1980s-2000s (Box 53)
    - Correspondence, printed material, and photographs, 1980s-2000s (Box 54)
    - Talking Pictures, writings, printed material, leaflets, photocopies, posters, The Legacy of Gaile Vazbys, and press kits, 1980s-2000s (Box 55)
    - Photographs, 1960s-1990s (Box 56)
    - Photographs, 1960s-1990s (Box 57)
    - Photographs, 1960s-1990s (Box 48 (Oversize))
    - Photographs, pen and ink drawings, 1973-1991 (Box 43 (Oversize))
  - Louise Landes-Levi
    - Correspondence, typescript, photographs, printed material, and ephemera, 1980s-2000s (Box 58)
    - Correspondence, typescript, photographs, printed material, and ephemera, 1980s-2000s (Box 59)
- Manuscript materials and working files, circa 1961-2007; Series IV; 29
  - Printed material, manuscripts, photocopies, correspondence, artwork, and photographs, 1961-2007 (Box 60)
  - Writings on Iraq; "Shamanic Warriors Now Poets" manuscript; Proofs for Minbad Sinbad and Petroleum Petroleum by Gustav Meyrink; photographs, and correspondence, 1989-2003 (Box 61)
  - Manuscripts, typescripts, printed material, photocopies, notes, photographs, photo prints, correspondence, writings, artwork, newspapers, and clippings, 1990s-2000s (Box 62)
  - Printed material, manuscripts, clippings, photocopies, 1970s-2000s (Box 63 (Oversize))
  - Printed material, photocopies, manuscripts, clippings, correspondence, photographs, notebook, and ephemera, 1975-2007 (Box 64)
  - Printed material, manuscripts, postcards, artwork, photography, photo prints, correspondence, writings, contact sheets, and mail art, 1970s-2000s (Box 65)
  - Mylar photographs, mail art, and correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 66)
  - Printed material, photocopies, photographs, clippings, correspondence, artwork, and ephemera, 1961-2007 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence, photographs, photocopies, artwork, printed material, manuscripts, and clippings, 1990s-2000s (Box 68)
  - Photocopies, writings, notes, postcards, printed material, negatives, photo prints, clippings, correspondence, and mail art, 1980s-2000s (Box 69)
  - Photographs, collages, and posters, 1980s-2000s (Box 70 (Oversize))
  - Correspondence, mail art, artwork, and ephemera, 1990s-2000s (Box 71)
  - Mail art, manuscripts, photographs, and ephemera, 1970-2000's (Box 72)
  - Photograph collage, laser scans, and posters, 1980-2000s (Box 70 (Oversize))
  - Postcards, printed materials, photocopies, artwork, correspondence, ephemera, writings, clippings, and photographic prints, 1980s-2000s (Box 73)
  - Photocopies, writings, photographs, printed material, contact prints, artwork, postcards, correspondence, clippings, financial registers, and ephemera, 1980s-2000s (Box 74)
  - Photocopies, photo prints, writings, artwork, printed material, correspondence, printed material, and journals, 1980s-2000s (Box 75)
  - Postcards, printed materials, photocopies, artwork, correspondence, ephemera, manuscripts, clippings, and photographic prints, 1970s-1990s (Box 76)
  - Printed materials, correspondence, artwork, news clippings, photographs, writings, and LSD blotter art, 1980s-2000s (Box 77)
  - Printed material, photocopies, gallery pamphlets, correspondence, writings, mail art, fliers, political stamps, photographs, postcards, AXIOM booklet, Gerard Malanga photographs, Ira Cohen photographs, Marco Bakker photographs, artwork, and address card file box, 1980s-2000s (Box 78)
  - Posters, notes, mail art, printed materials, copy of "Gabrielle d'Estees et une de se soeurs" annotated by Ira Cohen, 1980s-2000s (Box 79 (Oversize))
  - Printed material, transcripts, writings, correspondence, mail art, photocopies, postcards, photo prints, photographs, Japanese writing books, journal, fliers, artwork, and contact prints, 1980s-2000s (Box 80)
  - Printed materials, writings, artwork, photographs, photo prints, correspondence, postcards, ephemera, notebooks, and address books, 1980s-2000s (Box 81)
  - Manuscript for Celestial Graffiti and related printed materials, artwork, correspondence, photographs, photo prints, news clippings, and ephemera, 1990s-2000s (Box 82)
  - Photographs, photo prints, artwork, correspondence, printed materials, 1990s-2000s (Box 83)
  - Signed digital prints by Kirke Wilson including "Shepardess" and other inkjet prints, correspondence, photographs, news clippings, ephemera, and mail art, 1980s-2000's (Box 84)
  - News clippings, manuscripts, correspondence, mail art, and ephemera, 1980s 1990s (Box 85)
  - Correspondence, photographs, mail art, ephemera, and other printed materials, 1990s (Box 86)
  - Correspondence, ramblings, photographs, mail art, and ephemera, 1980s-1990s (Box 87)
  - Artwork, photographs, mail art, and ephemera, 1960s-1990s (Box 88)
  - Material related to Petra Vogt, 1970s (Box 98a (Oversize))
  - Material related to Petra Vogt, 1970s (Box 99)
  - Material related to Petra Vogt and Ira Cohen's time in Kathmandu, 1970s-1980s (Box 100)
  - Material related to Ira Cohen's time in Kathmandu, 1980s (Box 101)
  - Travel diaries, 1970s-1980s (Box 102)
  - Correspondence, ephemera, photographs, noted, and typescripts, 1970s-2000s (Box 103)
- Notebooks, 1979-2005; Series V; 4
  - Notebooks, including datebooks and notepads, 1979-2001 (Box 89)
  - Notebooks, including datebooks and notepads, 2002-2005 (Box 90)
  - Notebooks, including holographic manuscripts, photocopied manuscripts and typescripts, correspondence, travel journals, and business cards, 1985-2007 (Box 91)
  - Notebooks, including composition books and address books, 1982-1999 (Box 92)
- Photographs, 1960s-2000s; Series VI; 37
  - Black and white photographs of, New York, Budapest, family, Diety - Nutsand, Halloween 1999, Cambodia, Cambodian prison museum, Johnny, Vali, Zoe, and Iris, 1990s-2000s (Box 104)
  - New York, Budapest, Cambodia, Johnny, Vali, Zoe, Iris, and family, 1990s-2000s (Box 105)
  - Photograph albums, color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1980s-2000s (Box 106)
    Includes Julian Beck funeral image; family photographs; Gerard Malanga; Uder Heyden / Images of Turkey; pictures of jewelry; Paul and Susan Savage in Pan / Steve D. and Yeko - Chinese poet; Herbie, David with guitar; Coney Island with GSM [Gerard Malanga], also Buck solo shoot; Naples 2003; Gerard Malanga's 60th [birthday] at Diane Hersey and Robert Whelan and Lunch with Baums; Natasha negatives; Marty Matz in the [Hello Oliver] room at the Carton, April 2000; and photographs from Robert W. Yarra.
  - Vali, Yankee Stadium, New York, Italy, Woodstock, Chris, Paul Bloom, Bus Trip, Isabella, and Living Theater? (Box 107)
  - Friends, New York, Hawl, Paola, and Harvey Keitel, 1984; 1990-2000s (Box 108)
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1990s-2000s (Box 109)
    Photographs of friends and family, including Michelle and Raphael, Taylor Mead, Jack and Aggie, Eric, Michael, Terri, Nina, Morgan, Lakshmi, Billy Foles, Barbara, Lawrence, A. Farley, Lionel, Bobby Y., Radha, John Solt, Mikki, Louise, Schiller, and including subjects in costume; photographs of Thailand, Cambodia, LA, and Budapest; photographs of arts and cultural events; and photographs of Ira Cohen.
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1990s-2000s (Box 110)
    Photographs of friends and family, including Marvin, Judith, Tom, Ruthie, Steve, John and Dianne, Eric LaPrade, Cynthia, Diane, Magdalena, Jivamarkti, Laswell, Janet, Sheldon and M., and including subjects in costume; photographs of Cambodia; photographs labeled Andover, Earth's Arc, and Sprachsalz; photographs of arts and cultural events; invitations, blank postcards, and a postcard from Ethiopia to Raphael Gladdin; and photographs of Ira Cohen.
  - Charlie's 70th?, Bissinger, Tom Savage, Cynthia, New York, friends and family, 2000s (Box 111)
  - New York, friends and family, 2000s (Box 112)
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1980s-2000s (Box 113)
    Includes Robert Beer, Marty Matz, Buck and Friends, "Oct 98 Carlo McCormich, Nathal… grapes, Paul under sign, Ken Brown," Judith Malina and Hanon Reznikov; Lakshmi Cohen, "Pink Pony with Mark Deutsch, Benjamin Lantchof, etc," "Family and friends – Lakshmi, Raphael, Roberto Valenza, Judith Malina; Chelsea Hotel, Malina, Ira L., etc. Feb 14 2005, Vali day," "Photo Marie, St. Hurbert," Gerard Malanga, Bissinger, "Suzi W, metro…," Victoria French, "Women of Istanbul, songs of outlaws," "EDW Field, Neil Derrick and Raphael Gabor and Barbara with Crown, etc, Romy and Foxy with Vaccaro," "Nov 98 Portland Walt C with pumpkins, etc," "Marjorie / Wood sculpture and Victoria and Cassie," "July 97 Baba (Nuyorican) Metabass, Hassan and Ira, CUNY," "Nov 98 Portland, Walt Curtis, Carl Hannover, see Panorama, C. Gutha, Victoria," "July 97 Marian Z, Caz, Cynthia, Ira with 10th St. Wall murals."
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1980s-2000s (Box 114)
    Includes Lakshmi Cohen, "Summer 98, Buck, Maria, Carlo, Sloppy, Baba, Tony Fish, Chitra, Nedgy and Ming," and "Sept 98 rebearing for J.B. Pey at Ira's Lord's Loft, Don Snyder, Paul and Julie Falk."
  - New York, Zurich, Gate of Hell, Debbie Harry, Billy Forbes, Alice, Gerard and Asako Wedding, John Hersey, friends and family, 2000s (Box 115)
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1990s-2000s (Box 116)
    Photographs of foreign travels (including Turkey, Zurich, and Naples), arts and cultural events (including readings, plays, and concerts), arrangements of objects, and friends and family. Includes Ira Cohen, Brad, Lois, Robert Whelan, Marina, Lakshmi (also includes photographs by Lakshmi), Sprachsalz, Jose Oliver, Robt W., R. and Cynthia, Michael R., Ferdinando and Judith, Ondi, Raphael, Bob Horito and Lauren, 3 doormen, Allan G., Michelle W., Jason W., Robert and Tia, Eric LaPrade, Swami and Herbert, "The Three Sages," Billy, pictures with note from Robert W. Yarra, Bobby Y., Michael and Jena, Alice F., Mariana Rydwal, the Tibet House, Lawrence W. celebration, Adam, Louise and D., Bhajan. Also includes notes or poems by Ira, one about September 11th, and postcards.
  - Color and black and white photographs and negatives, 1990s-2000s (Box 117)
    Photographs of arrangements of objects, arts and cultural events, and friends and family. Includes Ira Cohen, Louise and David (Rosita), Ben Hayeem, Marc Platt, Marina, Lawrence W., Roma, Hannelore and M. and David Goldstein, Cynthia and Wolf Lureen, Raphael Rimbaud, Suzi, Allan Gravbard, and Michael Rothenberg.
  - Photographs by Georg Gatsas, David A. Sands, and others, All Beings Day Golden Gate Park November 1981, 1980s-2000s (Box 118)
  - Photographs by Ira Cohen, Anne Nordmann, Gilles Larrain, Clayton Patterson, Carol Beckwith, Don Snyder, Gerard Malanga, and Max Klinger, 1970s-2000s (Box 119)
  - Photographs by Ira Cohen, Anne Nordmann, Gilles Larrain, Clayton Patterson, Carol Beckwith, Don Snyder, Gerard Malanga, and Max Klinger, 1970s-2000s (Box 120 (Oversize))
  - Black and white and color photographs and large prints, 1970s-2000s (Box 121)
    Includes photographs of Ira Cohen and other subjects by (or from): Peter Cunningham, Indra Tamang, Marcia Resnick, Ira Landgarten, Francesco Masci, Joe Geitler, Hisashi, Jan and Lois Alsop, Bruce Carpenter, Charlz (Charles) Junod, Maurizio Rugger (Ruggeri), Isabel, Karen Hershey, David Sands, Misao, Larry Sawyer, Susan Falk, E., Asako, Marco Bakker, Mia Hanson, Ellen Pearlman, Christopher Stein, Gary Halpern, Matthew Lewis, John Beigelow Taylor, Gail Parker, P. Segura, Emily (with note), Karin (with note), Hibbard (with note), Wird Oudejans (with note), I. (with note), John Taylor, Vali Myers, A. Parker, Hawk, Hallie, Filipa, Billy, Eric LaPrade, J.N. and Ann Reilly, H. Thalmann, Francesca.
    Labels include: Elegea for Allen, Don Snyder, Gregory and his daughter - nurse Sheri, Anita Fiset, For Trawdi Duck, Shiv Mirabito, Gregory's funeral, Chili, Tambri, Jack Barker, Ira giving readings, Pour Ira Cohen, Alhambra 1929, Jade Hirschmann reading poetry at his book party, For Jon, love Bing, Gerard Malanga (stationary on which note is written), Ram Nath, Hannelore Rezzomico (note regarding her), P.S. 1 Contemporary Art Center, Charles Henri Ford, John - Michelle - Teny - Wilson, Ed Nielson (poem), St. Valentines Day '05 - Hotel Chelsea, Sumita - my little "adopted" Nepali girl, Didi with baby doing Puja, Ignite Magazine release party, Rolend Valery, Raphael Aladdin Cohen.
    Places include London, Brussels, New York, Crete, Erlangen. Also includes photographs by Ira Cohen, photographs of family and friends, objects, and events with music and costumes. Also includes some documents, artwork, cards, ephemera.
  - Vieled Somali woman, Somalia by Carol Beckwith and Angela Fisher; Ira Cohen; double profile of Ira Cohen, 1980s (Box 122 (Oversize))
  - Photographs from the Mylar Chamber project with Williams S. Burroughs, Bill Laswell and Nicky Scopelitis, photographs from a Poetry Festival in Switzerland, photograph transparencies prepared for printing, photographs of Micheal john Anerson, Ed Koch, Andy Warhol, Brion Gysin, and others, photographs by Ira Cohen, Indra Tomang, Bernie Mindich, 1960s-2000s (Box 123)
  - Photographs from the Mylar Chamber project with Williams S. Burroughs, Bill Laswell and Nicky Scopelitis, photographs from a Poetry Festival in Switzerland, photographic transparencies prepared for printing, photographs of Micheal John Anerson, Ed Koch, Andy Warhol, Brion Gysin, and others, photographs by Ira Cohen, Indra Tomang, Bernie Mindich, 1960s-2000s (Box 124)
  - Photographs of geodesic dome construction with William S. Burroughs and Brian Gysin, other photographs of Nicky Scopelitis and Vali Myers, 1980s-1990s (Box 125 (Oversize))
  - Photographs of Ira Cohen, friends and family, art and arrangements of objects, arts and cultural events (including readings and concerts), pets, and hospital visits, 1990s-2000s (Box 126)
    Labels and subjects include: Lakshmi, "Cage au Folle," Phyllis Segura, "Woodstock - Chris and Alaia B.," Mariana, "2 Iras with English" (photo by John Solt), Bonnie, Hirschman, Aggie, Ondi, Ira Landgarten, Gigi, Petulia, Dala, Aidan, John, Brandi, Gerard, Foxy, "God Photos CHF & GM."
  - Photographs of Ira Cohen, friends and family, art and arrangements of objects, and arts and cultural events, 1990s-2000s (Box 127)
  - Photographs of Weisburg, Marina Van der Heijden, Deer France, Billy Swofford, Shiv Mirabito, North Madison, CT, Sabrina, Lucia Dee France, Lawell, Rine Lucien, Jefferson Carre, 1990s-2000s (Box 128)
  - Photographs of friends and family, New York, and Shiv Mirabito, 1990s-2000s (Box 129)